ASHWIN KUMAR.C

Mobile: +91 9566060363 | E-mail: cashwinkumar30@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVES

A challenging career in growing professional organizations to utilize the essential element of my qualification, experience and interest.

PERSONAL PROFILE

5+ years of experience in environment health & safety management and fire fighting. Possess in-depth understanding of various safety methods & proven abilities in coordinating and leading variety of people with an ability to develop strategic plans. Inspection aspects in different types of safety methods and method additionally worked for ISO quality systems to achieve company goals.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hindustan Institute of Maritime Training (February 2017 to April 2018)

Designation: Safety Inspector *Duties and Responsibilities:*

- Review of sub-contractor Safety procedures and approval
- Site audit at sub-contractor safety facilities
- Conducting safety meetings
- Maintenance of all equipment's in Mockup
- Handling all the documentations in Mockup
- Taking classes in the Mockup about Fire Fighting

Fire Care Systems and Equipment (October 2015 to September 2016)

Designation: Safety Engineer *Duties and Responsibilities:*

- Preparation of written practices as per industry applicable codes/standards
- Review of sub-contractor Safety procedures and approval
- Site audit at sub-contractor safety facilities
- Conducting safety meetings, Procurement of PPE
- Lead a team of 10+ Safety officers at normal operation time and 30+ during Turnarounds

AK Engineers and Contractors (April 2014 to September 2015)

Designation: Safety Engineer *Duties and Responsibilities:*

- Preparation of written practices as per industry applicable codes/standards
- Review of sub-contractor, safety procedures and approval
- Site audit at sub-contractor safety facilities
- Conducting Daily Toolbox Talk, procurement of PPE for the works

MJK Construction (September 2013 to February 2014)

Designation: Safety Engineer *Duties and Responsibilities:*

- Preparation of written practices as per industry applicable codes/standards
- Review of sub-contractor Safety procedures and approval
- Conducting Daily Toolbox Talk

V K Design Techniques India Pvt. Ltd (June 2012 to May 2013)

Designation: Safety Supervisor *Duties and Responsibilities:*

- Conducting Site induction
- Conducting Daily Toolbox Talk
- Safety procedures and approval Site audit at sub-contractor, safety facilities

PROFFESIONAL RESPONSIBILITIES

- Conduct daily safety inspections to identify unsafe acts, unsafe conditions and adopt preventive measures
- Advising the management on matters pertaining to HSE aspects
- Management of policies and procedures covering Health, Safety and Environment
- Motivating the workforce and keep their moral up in HSE aspects
- Organizing HSE trainings programs for all employees and maintaining records
- Organizing & Conducting mock drills to management employees
- Carryout periodic inspection of vehicles, machineries, equipment, tools, lifting cranes, PPE for HSE adequacy and follow up for timely corrective actions
- Coordinating necessary documentation for internal and external audits
- Rendering required assistance to the line management in investigation of incidents, accidents and to avoid recurrence
- Close monitoring of the safety violations, find out the reason for that and take steps to avoid recurrence
- Maintaining 5S in the work place and maintaining daily checklist in site, organization
- Regular audits & checking hydrant valves, coupling and water pressure, safety handling equipment, pumps, detectors
- Issuing safety work permits like hot work, cold work, vessel entry and height work permit systems
- Coordinate first aid, rescue and emergency services in the organization
- Ensure that wastes generated from the work creates minimal hazard to the environmental rules and regulations

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

- Certification on Scaffolding safety, Chennai, 2016
- PG Diploma in FIRE AND SAFETY (BSS), 2014
- B.Tech, Mechanical Engineering from BHARATH UNIVERSITY, 2012
- 12th from Rajkumar Sulochana School (Science & Maths), 2008
- 10th from Hindu Colony Chellammal Vidyalaya, 2006